Guide to the Gay Cable Network Archives 1982-2001 MSS 231
© 2012 Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series XXII: Pride and Progress / The Right Stuff
  - Subseries A: Cablecast Programs, 1985-1990
    - 1984
      - [1]--Pride and Progress. Episode No. 1 [2]--The Right Stuff, Episode No. 118 [Air Date: 10/4/1984] (Box 39, Media ID: 231.0599)
        COMMERCIAL: Chamberlain and Associates, career service professionals
        COMMERCIAL: "New York Native"
        8. Three teens charged in death of Charles Howard, a gay man in Maine
        9. Interview with Vivian Shapiro, Human Rights Campaign
        COMMERCIAL: "The Connect"
        Healthline: Conversations with GMHC: Dr. Steven Caiazza discusses "How to Reduce Risk of Getting AIDS"
        COMMERCIAL: World of Video
        The Right Stuff:
        COMMERCIAL: National Fund for Human Dignity with Abigail "Dear Abby" Van Buren
        COMMERCIAL: Pensione, San Francisco Hotel
        1. Interview with Phyllis Diller, entertainer
        COMMERCIAL: H. Clay Friedrichs Realtors, New Jersey
        COMMERCIAL: Rio Adventure, Orpheo travel agency
        2."Brothers," a Showtime cable comedy series
        COMMERCIAL: "People in Touch," a gay dating service
        3. "Fever of an Unknown Origin" - Interviews with actor playwright Stephen Holt, actor Raymie Priesmeyer, scenes from the play
        COMMERCIAL: Spur Productions
        4. Phyllis Diller interview/ closing credits
        COMMERCIAL National Fund for Human Dignity with Judge Steven Lax
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 2 [2]--The Right Stuff, Episode No. 119 [Air Date: 10/5/1984] (Box 39, Media ID: 231.0601)
        Original Format: 3/4 in. Umatic
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 3 [2]--The Right Stuff, Episode No. 120 [Air Date:10/13/1984] (Box 39, Media ID: 231.0602)
        1. Sentencing of Maine teens in death of Charles Howard, a gay man
        2. San Francisco rejects extending employment benefits to gay partners of city workers
        3. First Ronald Reagan versus Walter Mondale debate viewed by gay Mondale supporters
        4. Sports Report
        5. Interview with Ivan [Deeds] about Gay Narcotics Anonymous
        6. Sweden as a place for political asylum for gays
        7. Sentencing of Gary Lee Hopper, a male hustler, in slashing and attempted robbery of gay man
        8. Gay center opens in Allentown, Pennsylvania
        9. Interview with Peter Vogel, Chairperson for New York Gay Task Force
        10. Interview with Peter Guardino, Gay Police Officers Action League
        11. Proposal to make West Hollywood a city
        Healthline: Conversations with GMHC: Dr. Scott Croxson, Fellow Immunopathology, discusses HTLV virus
        COMMERCIAL: "The Connection," a gay newspaper
        COMMERCIAL: National Fund for Human Dignity with actor Mike Farrell
        1. Footage from San Francisco memorial for John Simms, who passed away from AIDS
        2.Interview with director Robert Epstein, producer Richard Schmiechen, and publicist Vito Russo, "The Times of Harvey Milk"
        3. "Swan in Love," commentary and clips about motion picture
        COMMERCIAL National Fund for Human Dignity with actor Jack Albertson
        4. More from interviews about "The Times of Harvey Milk"/ closing credits
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 4 [2]--The Right Stuff, Episode No. 121 [Air Date: 10/22/1984] (Box 39, Media ID: 231.0603)
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 5 [2]--The Right Stuff, Episode No. 122 [Air Date: 10/24/1984] (Box 39, Media ID: 231.0604)
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 6 [2]--The Right Stuff, Episode No. 123 [Air Date: 11/6/1984] (Box 39, Media ID: 231.0605)
        1. New York Executive Order #50 - a non-discrimination policy on city contactors
        2. Interview with Willy Smith, Gay and Lesbian Inter-Religious Coalition
        COMMERCIAL: "New York Native," with Quentin Crisp
        3. Interview with Nancy Roth, executive director of Gay Rights National Lobby, Washington D.C.
        COMMERCIAL: Chamberlain and Associates, Career Service Professionals
        4. AIDS fears in court
        5. Interview with Tim Sweeney, director of LAMBDA Legal Defense, discussing LAMBDA's AIDS Legal Guide
        COMMERCIAL: "Rome Adventure," Orpheo Travel Agency
        6. Interview with Reverend Karen Zeigler, director of Metropolitan Community Church, discussing their on-going application to the National Council of Churches
        COMMERCIAL: "The Times of Harvey Milk"
        7. Gay and lesbian child custody announcement
        8. LAMBDA Democrats, authors night
        COMMERCIAL: Arcos Blancos Resort, San Juan, Puerto Rico
        9. Heathline: Conversations with GMHC: Dr. Jeffrey Lawrence, NY Hospital, Cornell Medical Center, discusses new directions in treating AIDS
        10. Sports Report: Interview with Jim Link and Leslie Randolph, Rambler Soccer Club
        1. 1984 Halloween on Christopher Street, NYC
        COMMERCIAL: "The Connection," gay/lesbian newspaper
        2. Lo Nardo, music group, performing
        3. Broadway star Vivian Blaine performing "live" at SAGE Benefit at the Limelight, NYC. Songs: "Guys and Dolls medley"
        4. Media Report: "Hollywood Babylon II," Japanese condoms, Cardinal Spellman, Michael Musto receives Village Voice column
        COMMERCIAL: Spur Production
        5. 1984 Halloween coverage/ Closing credits
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 7 [2]--The Right Stuff, Episode No. 124 [Air Date: 11/13/1984] (Box 39, Media ID: 231.0606)
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 8 [2]--The Right Stuff, Episode No. 125 [Air Date: 11/20/1984] (Box 39, Media ID: 231.0607)
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 9 [2]--The Right Stuff, Episode No. 126 [Air Date: 11/27/1984] (Box 39, Media ID: 231.0608)
        1. Interview with Nancy Roth, Executive Director, Gay Rights National Lobby, discussing anti-discrimination in immigration policy
        COMMERCIAL: Carnaval in Rio de Janeiro, Islanders' Club
        2. City status granted to West Hollywood, California; city council is formed
        3. Anti-gay Texas Senator Phil [Graham] wins election
        4. Gay Rights bill passed in Houston, Texas, but may be overturned
        COMMERCIAL: "New York Native" with Quentin Crisp
        5. Interview with David Bender, campaigner, discussing the win of Massachusetts' openly gay Senator Gary Studds
        COMMERCIAL: New York Gay Film Festival
        6. National Gay Task Force meeting
        COMMERCIAL: "The Connection," gay and lesbian newspaper
        7. Interview with Pastor Karen Zeigler, Metropolitan Community Church, discusses meeting with National Council of Churches
        8. First census of a gay community, San Francisco
        9. Carol Bellamy, announcement of upcoming appearance
        COMMERCIAL: Arcos Blancos, San Juan, Puerto Rico
        10. Healthline: Conversations with GMHC: Christopher Collins, attorney, discusses the start of Community Health Project
        COMMERCIAL: "Badlands," a NYC gay bar
        11. Sports Report/ closing
        1. Media Report/ Current Events
        2. Terry Miller interviews Quentin Crisp, author/ performer
        3. Quentin Crisp interview continued
        COMMERCIAL: National Fund for Human Dignity for disabled gays and lesbians
        4. Preview of upcoming gay motion picture, "Whispers"
        5. Interview with Ron Gould, producer of gay film "Whispers"/ closing credits
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 10 [2]--The Right Stuff, Episode No. 127 [Air Date: 12/3/1984] (Box 39, Media ID: 231.0609)
        1. "Black and White Men Together" members Lidell Jackson and Mitchell Karp discuss racial discrimination at the Ice Palace
        2. National Gay Task Force, interviews with members Peter Fowler and Evelyn White
        3. Interview with Keith O'Connor, NYC Human Rights Commission, discussing anti-gay discrimination bill in NYC
        COMMERCIAL: Carnaval in Rio de Janiero, The Islanders Club
        4. Report on Executive Order 50; employment rights for city contractors
        5. U.S. Court of Appeals for District of Columbia refused to hear case of expelled gay navy officer
        6. Community announcements
        COMMERCIAL: Arco Blancos resort, San Juan, Puerto Rico
        7. Heathline: Conversations with GMHC: Topic: AIDS Assessment Program of Community Health Project. Interview with Dr. Ted Lazarus, clinical coordinator AIDS Assessment Program, and Rona Affoumado, Admin. Director, Community Health Project
        COMMERCIAL: Badlands, NYC gay bar
        8. Sports report
        1. Current Events
        2. Interview with Gary Miller, music director of the NYC Gay Men's Chorus, includes footage of chorus performing at Christopher Street Liberation Day Parade 1984
        COMMERCIAL: New York Gay and Lesbian Film Festival
        COMMERCIAL: NGTF Fund for Human Dignity: gay and lesbian disabled
        4. Interview with Quentin Crisp
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 11 [2]--The Right Stuff, Episode No. 128 [Air Date: 12/4/1984] (Box 39, Media ID: 231.0610)
        1. Nancy Roth, executive director of Gay Rights National Lobby, discusses history of National Gay Rights Bill
        2. [Greg Merkus] discusses upcoming Winter Solstice fundraiser at the new Community Center
        3. Dr. Mervin Silverman talks to New York Physicians For Human Rights discussing his concerns over the re-opening of bathhouses in San Francisco
        4. "Black and White Men Together" members Lidell Jackson and Mitchell Karp discuss racial discrimination
        5. Keith O'Connor, NYC Human Rights Commission, discusses gay discrimination
        6. Judges decision in the Dronenberg case challenges right to privacy
        COMMERCIAL: "The Gascon," a novel by John Colin Penford
        7. Report on the test for HTLV and fears of misuse
        8. Healthline: Conversations with GMHC: Topic: Mental Health, Depression during the holidays. Interview with Chuck Jones, Director of Intake, GMHC
        9. Sports report
        10. Current Events
        GCN Special Presentation: "Whispers," a gay docudrama
        1. "Whispers," a gay docudrama
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 12 [2]--The Right Stuff. Episode No. 129[Air Date: 12/18/1984] (Box 39, Media ID: 231.0611)
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 13 [2]--The Right Stuff, Episode No. 130 [Air Date: 12/26/1984] (Box 39, Media ID: 231.0612)
        1. A recap of some of the major LGBT events of 1984. Clips include:
        2. Original "Stonewallers" at Pride Parade
        3. Bella Abzug speech at Greater Gotham Business Meeting
        4. Virginia Apuzzo on LGBT presence at Democratic National Convention
        5. VP candidate Geraldine Ferraro at Democratic National Convention on human rights
        6. Maureen Reagan, daughter of President, interviewed at Republican National Convention
        7. Mayor Ed Koch at fundraiser for Judge Bill Thom
        8. David Rothenberg campaign speech
        10. Speech by Victor Gotbaum, Director DC 37, AFSCME
        11. [Fairpack], a new political gay action committee
        12. Reports on AIDS in 1984
        13. Report on gays on television in 1984, including Showtime's cable series "Brothers"
        14. Gay youth
        16. Acquisition of NYC's LGBT Community Center on West 13th Street
        15. Wrap up of 1984 events
        COMMERCIAL: Disc-o-rama, NY video and music store
        16. Healthline: Conversations with GMHC: Michael Shernoff, Chelsea Psychotherapy, discusses how to deal with friends who have AIDS
        17. Closing credits
        1. Performance by the Big Apple Corps Band with the Pink Panther
        2. Gary Dee, female impersonator, on playing Joan Rivers
        3. "Home for the Holidays," benefit at Limelight for AIDS Research Center (ARC), appearances by Whoopi Goldberg, Maurice Hines
        4. "Impulse," Gat TV in Atlanta
        5. Closing Credits
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 14 [2]--The Right Stuff, Episode No. 131 [Air Date: 12/31/1984], [1984/ 1985] (Box 39, Media ID: 231.0613)
        1. Gay rights hearings in Alexandria, Virginia
        2.Tom Stoddard, Legislative Director of New York Civil Liberties Union, discusses sodomy laws
        COMMERCIAL: Actor/ playwright Harvey Fierstein announces his return to "Torch Song Trilogy" at the Helen Hayes Theatre
        3. Latest news on San Francisco bathhouses
        4. New York Critics Circle names "The Times of Harvey Milk" film documentary of the year
        5.Book: "Family Dancing"
        6. Latest on gays and religion
        7. Reagan administration may strike down current immigration laws that prevent gays from entering U.S.
        8. Berkeley, California extends domestic partner benefits to city employees
        9. Healthline: Conversations with GMHC: Dr. Dennis Passar, board member NYPHR, discusses parasites
        10. Sports Report/ Closing
        1. Media Report/ Current Events, including clips from TV series "Fame" with appearance by Charles Pierce
        2. Interview with actor John Burke, on career and appearance in play "City Men"
        COMMERCIAL: "Manscape," a gay magazine
        3. Gary Dee, female impersonator, on playing Joan Rivers
        4. Interview with film director Reinhard von der Marwitz, discusses "Giarres"
        5. "Fame" clips/ closing credits
    - 1985
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 15 [2]--The Right Stuff, Episode No. 132 [Air Date: 1/7/1985] (Box 39, Media ID: 231.0614)
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 16 [2]--The Right Stuff, Episode No. 133 [Air Date: 1/17/1985] (Box 40, Media ID: 231.0615)
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 17 [2]--The Right Stuff, Episode No. 134 [Air Date: 1/23/1985] (Box 40, Media ID: 231.0616)
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 18 [2]--The Right Stuff, Episode No. 135 [Air Date: 1/29/1985] [3]--Healthline (Box 40, Media ID: 231.0617)
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 19 [2]--The Right Stuff, Episode No. 136 [Air Date: 2/5/1985] (Box 40, Media ID: 231.0618)
        1. Virginia Supreme Court child custody suit
        2. Tom Stoddard, Legislative Director of New York Civil Liberties Union, on legality of gay relationships
        3. Federal Gay Rights Bill reintroduced in U.S. House of Representatives
        4. Interview with Jeff Snow and Bonnie McGinley, spokepersons for Concerned Americans for Individual Rights
        5. The American Automobile Association in Wisconsin extends its benefits to gay couples
        6. Salvation Army in Wisconsin loses contract when it refuses to sign anti-discrimination clause
        7. Andy Humm discusses anti-gay rights activist, John J. O'Connor, Catholic Archbishop of New York
        8. Interview with Brent Nicholson, head of The American Run for the End of AIDS
        9. Sports Report
        10. Healthline: Conversations with GMHC: Elaine Noble, Addiction Recovery Corp. member, discusses alcohol and drug addiction in the gay community
        11. Closing credits
        1. Media reports/current events
        2. Valentine's Day edition of "Season's Eatings" with Joe Alleva
        3. Interview with Robert Rios, director of Dallas production of "Boys in the Band"
        3. On the Streets with Jon
        4. Closing credits
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 20 [2]--The Right Stuff, Episode No. 137 [Air Date: 2/12/1985] (Box 40, Media ID: 231.0619)
        News-highlights:
        1. New chairman of Democratic Party, Paul G. Kirk Junior, approves the removal of the caucus system, a gay/lesbian political conduit
        2. Interview with Jeff Snow and Bonnie McGinley, spokepersons for Concerned Americans for Individual Rights
        3. Philadelphia Commission on Human Relations/military Recruitment Conflict at Temple University
        4. Gay employment rights referendum does not pass in Houston, Texas, interview with Debra Danbury, state representative of Houston District #137
        5. 5th circuit of appeals reviews sodomy law that only includes homosexuals in Austin, Texas
        6. Openly gay and closeted politicians
        7. Sports
        8. Healthline: Conversations with GMHC: Interview with Joyce Hunter, Program Director at Institute For the Protection of Lesbian & Gay Youth, discusses shelters and counseling
        9. Closing credits
        1.Opening with Sybil Opthalmia Bruncheon
        2. Flower arrangements with Sybil Opthalmia Bruncheon
        3. Culture/media/current events
        4. Interview with The Women of Dallas
        COMMERCIAL: National Fund for Human Dignity with Mike Farrell
        5. On the streets with John Seidner
        6. Closing credits
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 21 [2]--The Right Stuff, Episode No. 138 [Air Date: 2/18/1985] (Box 40, Media ID: 231.0620)
        1. Virginia Apuzzo resigns from National Gay Task Force
        2. Virginia Apuzzo gives speech at press conference
        3. Reagan administration drastically cuts AIDS funding in 1986 budget
        4. French researchers develop new drug for AIDS treatment, HPA23
        4. ABC movie "Consulting Adults", viewership ratings and clip from film
        5. New Hampshire Bill proposes gay/lesbian blood donation as felony
        6. School administrators cancel Tolerance Day in Madison, Maine, because of lesbian speaker
        7. Commentary on LGBT civil rights
        8. Texas State Legislature representative Bill Ceverha, author of proposed Texas sodomy law
        9. West Hollywood and domestic partners ordinance
        10. San Francisco City Civil Service Commission rejects Public Health department request to hire private investigators for gay bathhouses
        11. "The Times of Harvey Milk" documentary acclaim
        12. Sports
        13. Healthline: Conversations with GMHC: Interview with Michele Schwartz, Coordinator of Senior Action in a Gay Environment
        14. Closing credits
        1. Sue Cavin, president of the Gay and Lesbian Press Association, discusses censorship in the New York Times
        2. Media reports/current events/culture
        3. Sybil Opthalmia Bruncheon takes ill
        4. Cooking with Sybil Opthalmia Bruncheon
        COMMERCIAL: National Fund for Human Dignity with Jack Albertson
        5. Closing credits
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 22 [2]--The Right Stuff, Episode No. 139 [Air Date: 2/26/1985] (Box 40, Media ID: 231.0621)
        1. HTLV testing delay and false positive rate
        2. Gerry Studds regains chairmanship of the house subcommittee on coastguard and navigation
        COMMERCIAL: "Lust in the Dust"
        3. Kings County Council in Washington state proposes an updated anti-gay discrimination ban for employment
        4. More on West Hollywood and domestic partners ordinance
        5. More on school administrators cancel Tolerance Day in Madison, Maine, because of lesbian speaker
        6. Commentary on Bernard Goetz, "subway vigilante"
        7. Los Angeles Mayor Tom Bradley fails to appoint more high level positions to openly gay people and promises to do better if re-elected
        8. Councilman John Goodner of Houston, Texas plans to challenge current pro-gay mayor, Kathy Whitmire
        9. Sue Lovell becomes first female president of Houston's Gay Political caucus
        10. Erie, Pennsylvania Judge questions validity of gay man's will, specifies nearly 120,000 dollar donation to further gay civil rights
        10. Big Brother accepts any volunteers no matter his/her sexual orientation
        11. Sports, interview with Tom Hull, commissioner of MCAA Big Apple Softball
        12. Weather report
        13. Healthline: Conversations with GMHC: Sara T. Beatrice, Chief of Virology Labs, New York City Department of Health, discusses HTLV 3 test
        1. Media reports/current events/culture
        2. "Rags of the 80s" Fashion show footage at The Limelight
        3. Interview with Dr. Jim Serafini on counseling both straight and gay men
        4. Interview with William Hoffman and Marshall Mason, playwright and director of play "As Is"
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 23 [2]--The Right Stuff, Episode No. 140 [Air Date: 3/5/1985] (Box 40, Media ID: 231.0622)
        1. Update on Human Rights Commission documenting anti-gay discrimination
        2. Interview with Keith O'Connor, Director of Discrimination for the NYC Human Rights Commission
        3. Supreme court refuses to hear Ohio high school guidance counselor's gay discrimination case
        4. National Gay Task Force Versus Oklahoma City schools
        5. Baltimore city council members vote against gay civil rights (anti-discriminatory) law
        6. Carol Bellamy, President of the New York City council, runs for mayor, includes clip of Bellamy at Greater Gotham Business Council
        7. The Foundation For Traditional Morality blames rise in AIDS to overturned Dallas sodomy law
        8. Local Dallas insurance agent misrepresents cancer plan to bar owners, says it includes AIDS, AIDS insurance plans
        9. Washing D.C. gay activists ask city to help fund AIDS education, counseling, and services
        10. Reagan administration lacks AIDS funding support
        11. Inter-faith Forum clip on Religion and AIDS
        13. Healthline: Conversations with GMHC: Christopher Collins, Cooperating Attorney with LAMBDA Legal Defense and Education Fund, discusses HTLVIII test
        1. Media reports/current events/culture including Reagan rap and "Pleasure Beach" clip
        [COMMERCIAL: "Lust in the Dust"]
        2. Barbara Esposito and Bruce Hopkins start gay comedy night at Paper Moon, clips and outtakes
        3. Interview with psychologist, Dr. Jim Serafini, discusses AIDS and sex fears
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 24 [2]--The Right Stuff, Episode No. 141 [Air Date: 3/12/1985] (Box 40, Media ID: 231.0623)
        1. Food and Drug Administration licenses HTLV III test amid doubts of its accuracy
        2. LAMBDA Defense fights HTLVIII test, may sue Food and Drug Administration for unacceptably high false positive rates
        3. Mariposa Foundation's Bruce Vogler discovers spermicide that eliminates HTLVIII on contact
        4. Update on Supreme Court cases, National Gay Task Force Versus Oklahoma City schools
        5. Interview with Tom Stoddard Legislative Director of New York Civil Liberties Union, discusses gay civil rights and Supreme Court cases
        6. Future of gay civil rights
        7. Anti-gay violence/harassment in Texas
        8. Minneapolis gym owner closes his business rather than abide by city's gay ordinances
        9. Zelda Rubinstein works for Los Angeles AIDS education group, appears on posters and ads, includes clip from "Poltergeist"
        10. Sports
        11. Healthline: Conversations with GMHC: Christopher Collins, Cooperating Attorney with LAMBDA Legal Defense and Education Fund, returns and discusses HTLVIII test
        12. Closing credits
        1. Media reports/current events/culture including Sammy Davis Junior clip and CBS HTVLIII coverage
        2. Restaurant review
        3. Sybil Bruncheon
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 25 [2]--The Right Stuff, Episode No. 142 [Air Date: 3/19/1985] (Box 40, Media ID: 231.0624)
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 26 [2]--The Right Stuff, Episode No. 143 [Air Date: 3/26/1985] (Box 40, Media ID: 231.0625)
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 27 [2]--The Right Stuff, Episode No. 144 [Air Date: 4/2/1985] (Box 40, Media ID: 231.0626)
        1. New Hampshire votes against discriminatory blood bill
        2. Several men press brutality charges against Chicago police department after a gar bar raid
        3. Philadelphia police officers extort money from local gay bars, FBI sting operation reveals
        4. Zelda Rubinstein ads